What muscle memories do
we need to change in the
age of AI?
I built some apps and
websites for a few
clients,
for a small fee:
brokers, restaurant
owners, accountants.
I find myself building
the system under the
assumption that
eventually
this website and the
systems will be used by
multiple clients.
For example, when I
design the API, I make
sure they are very
extendable.
Basically, I was always
building a SaaS as an
assumption,
which is true for the
last decade.
But recently, I realized
that this is not the case
anymore.
When the next restaurant
owner, next broker, next
accountant reach out to
me,
I simply don't have to
inject his or her data
into any existing system
anymore.
I don't have to reuse any
of the existing code.
I can simply build a new
one.
Because the cost of
building something new is
so low these days,
we can afford to build
something from scratch
very fast.
We're talking about days,
or maximum weeks, and
then the new client will
have a working system.
And as a result, we can
hard-code a lot of things
in the system,
assuming that the
website, the app, the
system is only forever
going to be used
by one person, one
business, one entity.
So ask ourselves this
question: in the age of
AI,
what muscle memories do
we need to change?